nandosperiperi.com 2017-01-30

# Privacy Policy | Nando's

Introduction

1.1 Thank you for visiting the [http://www.nandosperiperi.com/ website](http://www.nandosperiperi.com/%C2%A0website) (the "Website"). Nando’s Peri-Peri (“Nando’s) is registered as Nando’s Restaurant Group, Inc. ("we", "us" or "our") and is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. 

1.2 This Privacy Policy, together with our Website terms and conditions available at [www.nandosperiperi.com/terms-service](http://www.nandosperiperi.com/terms-service), sets out the basis on which any personal information we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be used, stored and processed by us ("Collect").  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your Personal Data (as defined below) and how we will treat it.

1.3 In adopting this Privacy Policy, we wish to balance our legitimate business interests and your reasonable expectation of privacy.  Accordingly, we will take reasonable steps to prevent unauthorised access to, or disclosure of your Personal Data.  However, we do not guarantee that your Personal Data shall be 100% secure.

1.4 By continuing to use the Website, you agree to the terms and conditions set out in this Privacy Policy.  You agree that we may Collect Personal Data for the purposes of providing you with access to our Website and for any of the purposes listed in clause 3 below.

What types of Personal Data do we Collect?

2.1 The types of Personal Data that we may Collect includes information necessary for our legitimate business interests. This may include personal information which contains identifiable information such as (amongst other things) your first and last name, screen name, email address, postal address, physical address, telephone number, date of birth, details about your telephone device (e.g. mobile phone) and your telephone service provider and information related to providing products and services ("Personal Data").

2.2 We may also Collect other information, including your interests, preferences, purchasing behavior, transactional information, geographical location and demographics (e.g., age, gender, and income information). We may, on occasion, combine Personal Data we receive online with other records (such as those from telephone and direct purchases) to develop a customer profile relating to you.

2.3 We will attempt to limit the types of Personal Data we Collect to only that to which you consent (for example, in the context of online registration, competitions, message boards, surveys, polls, games, SMS, MMS and other mobile services). 

2.4 When you visit our Website, our web server also automatically records the name of your ISP (Internet Service Provider), the website from which you visit us, the pages on our sites you visit and in what sequence, and the date and length of your visit. This information is aggregate and anonymous data and does not identify you specifically.

Shopify  
3.1 Our store is hosted on Shopify Inc. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our products and services to you. Shopify’s privacy policy governs their collection and use of your information; it is available here. We contractually require that Shopify adhere to the standards set by the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standards. Information you provide in a purchase transaction is directly sent to Shopify; we do not receive any payment information from Shopify, only your order and shipping information.

How do we use your Personal Data?  
4.14.1     We may use your Personal Data to:

4.1.1      provide services or products you request (e.g. fulfilling any orders you place online or send you by email or other electronic means our newsletters or other products or services in which you express an interest);

4.1.2      allow you to participate in recreational activities on the Website (e.g. participate in our message boards), to organize or carry out promotional activities, games or promotional events;

4.1.3       inform you of changes made to our Website;

4.1.4      inform you of products, services, promotions, offers and competitions which you may find interesting, subject to clause 7 below;

4.1.5      respond to any queries you may have;

4.1.6      develop a more direct relationship with you for the purposes described in this section;

4.1.7       develop an online customer profile;

4.1.8       understand general customer trends and patterns so we can develop and support existing and ongoing marketing strategies for our products and services; and

4.1.9       for security, administrative and legal purposes.

4.2   Where you choose to receive mobile services and content via SMS, MMS and other mobile services, we use this information to deliver such mobile services and content to you, to carry out market research, to track sales data and to plan other promotional activities which may be of interest to you.

What is our Cookies Policy?

5.1  We, our third party service providers and our partners may send "cookies" to your computer or use similar technologies to enhance your online experience at our Website and across the Internet. "Cookies" are files that can identify you as a unique customer and store your personal preferences as well as product preferences, to tell us which site pages you have visited and in what order. We use cookies and other technical information to personalize your visit to the Website, to analyze traffic on the Website and to track user trends, patterns and selections for authorized download and for technical reasons connected with your use of our site. Cookies can either be permanent (i.e. they remain on your computer until you delete them) or temporary (i.e. they last only until you close your browser).

5.2   We utilize Google Analytics to analyze usage patterns of the Site.  Google Analytics generates a cookie to capture information about your use of the Site which Google uses to compile reports on website activity for us and to provide other related services.  Google may use a portion of your IP address to identify their cookie, but this will not be associated with any other data held by Google. From time to time we may implement additional features including  Remarketing with Google Analytics to place ads on other sites you may visit after visiting our site,  Google Display Network Impression Reporting to report how people’s interactions with our ads relate to their visits to our site, DoubleClick Platform integrations to help optimize our online advertising efforts, or Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to analyze information about our site visitors’ interests.  These tools help us to better understand your interests and how to provide you with more relevant online advertising. We and third party vendors, including Google, may use first and third party cookies together to optimize and serve ads tailored to you based, for example, on what parts of our site you viewed. To opt out of Google Analytics cookies please visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. To opt out of DoubleClick cookies please visit  <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin>. For more information about your cookies options visit  [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed. ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed.%C2%A0)

5.3     We may also use "web beacons" that monitor your use of our Website. Web beacons (or web bugs) are small strings of code that provide a method for delivering a graphic image on a web page for the purpose of transferring data, such as the IP (Internet Protocol) address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the web beacon appears, the URL (Uniform Resource Locator) of the page on which the web beacons appears, the time the page containing the web beacon was viewed, the types of browser that fetched the web beacon and the identification number of any cookie on the computer previously placed by that server. When corresponding with you via HTML capable e-mail, web beacons let us know whether you received and opened our email. On their own, cookies or web beacons do not contain or reveal any Personal Data. However, if you choose to provide us with Personal Data, it can be linked to the anonymous data stored in the cookies and/or web beacons. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. However, if you prefer, you may adjust your browser to reject cookies from us or from any other website. Additionally, by setting your web browser to display HTML emails as text only, you may be able to prevent the use of some web beacons. To the extent that your browser permits such ‘do-not-track’ settings, we will recognize that setting and exclude you from analytics that collect information about your online activities over time and across third party websites. However, please note that certain areas of our Website can only be accessed in conjunction with cookies or similar devices.

5.4     We permit limited third parties to place cookies through the Website to provide us with better insights into the use of the Site or user demographics or to provide relevant advertising to you.  These third parties may collect information about a consumer’s online activities over time and across different websites when he or she uses our website.  We do not control and are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties.

What about Personal Data that is publicly available?

6.1    If at any time our Website offers any chat rooms, message boards, blogs, newsgroups or forums, etc., we collect the information that you disclose. Such information will be used in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Please note that we are not responsible for other parties' use of the Personal Data which you make available to such third parties through any chat room, message board, blog, newsgroup or forums, etc. on our Website

Will my Personal Data be used for marketing purposes?

7.1     If we obtain your prior consent, we may use your Personal Data for the purposes of:

7.1.1      direct marketing of our own products and services and on behalf of other companies within Nando’s; and

7.1.2      direct marketing of products and services on behalf of selected third parties, if you have agreed to your details being passed onto third parties. 

7.2     You are entitled to request that we desist from using your Personal Data for the purposes of direct marketing, and we will provide you with the necessary functionality for you to do so with ease, each time we market to you. 

What security measures are in place to protect my Personal Data?

8.1     Although absolute security cannot be guaranteed on the Internet, we have in place up-to-date, reasonable technical and organizational security measures to protect your Personal Data against accidental or intentional manipulation, loss, misuse, destruction or against unauthorized disclosure or access to the information we collect online.

8.2     While we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any Personal Data you provide us, we will continue to maintain and improve these security measures over time in line with legal and technological developments.

How will we store your Personal Data?

9.1     We store your Personal Data. We may also or alternatively store your Personal Data on and transfer your Personal Data to a central database located in AWS.  If the location of the central database is located in a country that does not have substantially similar laws which provide for the protection of personal data, we will take the necessary steps to ensure that your Personal Data is adequately protected in that jurisdiction.

9.2     Your information will not be stored for longer than is necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Will my Personal Data be shared with anyone else?

10.1   Nando’s entities: We may share your Personal Data with other entities within Nando’s (i.e. any of the Nando’s affiliates under our control) that have agreed to be bound by this Privacy Policy. It is possible that we, or one of our divisions or affiliates, could merge with, be sold to or be or have all or part of our assets acquired by a third party. To the extent legally permissible and in accordance with the conditions of this Privacy Policy, we may share your Personal Data with any successor entity.

10.2 Third parties: We may disclose Personal Data about you to other third parties to comply with applicable laws and regulations and any governmental or legal requests or subpoenas. We also reserve the right to disclose such Personal Data to third parties where a complaint arises concerning your use of our Website and where we believe, in our sole discretion, that your use of our Website is inconsistent with the Privacy Policy or to protect our rights, property or safety or the rights, property or safety of our users or others. We also share information about users of this Website in an anonymous or aggregate form with third parties including advertisers and business partners, to understand customer trends and patterns and manage and improve our business relationships. We provide your Personal Data to third party agents or service providers to administer and process in order to assist us in the conduct of our business and for the purposes notified to you in this Privacy Policy, and we may also share such details with third parties (such as auditors or legal advisors) to obtain professional advice. Any such processing will be governed by an agreement in the form required by law, preserving any and all of your statutory data protection rights. Furthermore, certain functions on our Website (such as our careers page and order online functionality) may be operated by third party service providers whose privacy policy applies to information you provide using those features.

 10.3 Links, advertisers, third party sponsors and ad-servers: Our Website may contain links to other websites that are not covered by this Privacy Policy and where information practices may be different from ours. Users should consult the other sites' privacy policies on such third party sites before submitting any Personal Data, as we are not responsible for and have no control over Personal Data that is submitted to, or collected by, these third-party sites. On this Website, we sometimes offer content or programs that are sponsored by or co-branded with identified third parties (e.g. competitions or promotions). These third parties can obtain Personal Data that you voluntarily submit to them to make use of the offer. We are not responsible for the collection and use of your Personal Data by these third parties. However, you will be informed, at the point of collection of such personally identifiable information, if these third parties will obtain such information, how it will be processed and to whom it will be transferred. On our Website, third parties may present or serve advertisements, provide us with data collection, reporting and ad response measurement, as well as assist with delivery of relevant marketing messages and advertisements. These third parties may view, edit, or set their own cookies and may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you visit this Website. The use of these technologies by such third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by this Privacy Policy.

How can I find out what Personal Data Nandos holds about me?

11.1   To see the Personal Data we have collected through this Website that relates to you, to cancel it and/or to correct or update this Personal Data, please email us at [customerservice@nandosperiperi.com](mailto:customerservice@nandosperiperi.com). 

11.2   To protect your privacy and security we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access. If you have any additional questions about Personal Data we hold about you, please contact us at [customerservice@nandosperiperi.com](mailto:customerservice@nandosperiperi.com).

Application and our use of Facebook user data (where applicable)

12.1   Nando’s has an official application for iPhone, iPad, iPod and Android, available for download in certain countries (the "Official Application").  To check if the Official Application is available in your country and/or to find out more details about the Official Application please visit our Website.

12.2   The Official Application will access information from user’s Facebook accounts once they give us permission to do so whilst using the Facebook-related functionality of the application. Once permission is granted, the Official Application accesses a user’s friends list and location only. If the Official Application is not available, this clause 11.2 will not apply to you.

12.3   In addition, Nando's has a "Find Yourself" Facebook application that will access information from users' Facebook accounts once they give us permission to do so. Once permission is granted, the application accesses a user's name, gender, birthday, locale, email address and spice result. To find out more details about the "Find Yourself" Facebook application, please visit our Website. If the "Find Yourself" Facebook application is not available, this clause 11.3 will not apply to you.

Use of this website by children  
13.1   This Website is accessible to children under the age of 18. However, this website is not designed nor intended to be attractive to use by children under the age of 13 ("Minors").   We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from Minors.  If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any information to us.  If we are advised that we have inadvertently collected data from a Minor we will delete that data from our systems.  
13.2   We require children to consult with their parents before providing Personal Data. We also encourage parents to supervise their children's online activities by, for example, adopting parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers that help provide a child-friendly online environment. These tools can also prevent children from disclosing online their name, address, and other Personal Data without parental permission.

13.3   We encourage parents to talk to their children about the use of the Internet and information they disclose to websites.  

Changes to this Privacy Policy  
14.1  We from time to time post the Effective date of our Privacy Policy below, we may revise this Privacy Policy to reflect company initiatives, changes in the law or technology or changes in our practices regarding the collection and use of Personal Data. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted, with a new Effective Date, on this Website so that you are always informed of the latest version.  
14.2   We will not use or disclose Personal Data provided to us pursuant to this Privacy Policy in ways other than the ones described above, without informing you and providing you with the opportunity to consent to such modified conditions concerning the use and disclosure of your Personal Data.

Governing Law

15.1   The contents of this Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of Delaware.

15.2   If any provision of this Privacy Policy is judged to be illegal, void or unenforceable due to applicable law or by order of a court of competent jurisdiction it shall be deemed deleted and the continuation in full force and effect of the remainder of the provisions will not be prejudiced.

How can I contact Nandos? 

16.1   If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please feel free to contact Nando’s Customer Care, [customerservice@nandosperiperi.com](mailto:customerservice@nandosperiperi.com)

Effective Date: 1/1/2015
